<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dan Donoghue</title>
    <link>http://dan.donoghue.eu/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dan Donoghue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="http://dan.donoghue.eu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Redneck Windows Unattend.xml</title>
      <link>http://dan.donoghue.eu/redneck-windows-unattend-xml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 23:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dan.donoghue.eu/redneck-windows-unattend-xml/</guid>
      <description>So I wanted a base VHD boot image for my laptop so I can quickly create a new Windows installation without having to go through the tedium of running a bunch of WIM commands. The basic idea was to create one base image setup with drivers and updates, then Sysprep that image, and then I can create a new differencing VHD backed by that base image.
The only downside was that the Windows Out-of-box-&amp;ldquo;experience&amp;rdquo; (OOBE) slowed the whole process down by asking asinine questions about privacy and stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DHCP Option 121 Classless Static Route values</title>
      <link>http://dan.donoghue.eu/generating-option121-classless-static-route/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 21:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dan.donoghue.eu/generating-option121-classless-static-route/</guid>
      <description>Option 121, while incredibly usefull, sure is a fucking pig to use. The option tends to be specified using hexadecimal values of shortened IPv4 network addresses prepended with the CIDR notiation of the mask also in hex. This leads to something like option 121 hex 180a.0100.0a00.1efe in Cisco-ish. Wtf does that mean??
What is O-121 For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, DHCP O-121 is another way to provide routes to clients other than setting the default-gateway option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LSI2008 SAS Controller on EL9</title>
      <link>http://dan.donoghue.eu/lsi2008-on-el9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 17:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dan.donoghue.eu/lsi2008-on-el9/</guid>
      <description>Problem I&amp;rsquo;ve neglected my home server for a while now so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d upgrade it with some new boot SSDs and a case that isn&amp;rsquo;t hot-boxing my hard-drives. New boot drives, new OS; I decided to go with Rocky Linux 9.1 since CentOS has been fucked around with.
Part of this upgrade meant moving my existing HDDs off of the integrated SATA controller onto their own dedicated SAS controller with nice clean breakout cables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hire Me!</title>
      <link>http://dan.donoghue.eu/hire-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 23:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dan.donoghue.eu/hire-me/</guid>
      <description>Transcripts BSc Computer Networking (2014)
FdSc Computing, Networking, and Software Development (2013)
BTEC National Diploma, IT Practitioners (2011)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aria2 Web on EL7</title>
      <link>http://dan.donoghue.eu/aria2-web-on-el7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 04:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dan.donoghue.eu/aria2-web-on-el7/</guid>
      <description>Aria2 is a CLI download manager that can download files over several different protocols. I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to set something like this up for ages, as it&amp;rsquo;s better to download files on my server than to leave another machine turned on.
Install Aria2 and Apache&amp;rsquo;s httpd The following commands enable the EPEL repo, install aria2 and httpd, and adds a firewall rule to allow HTTP traffic from the public zone. If you&amp;rsquo;ve set up different zones (like I have), use the zone that you want to allow access from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the deal with pings?</title>
      <link>http://dan.donoghue.eu/whats-the-deal-with-pings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 19:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dan.donoghue.eu/whats-the-deal-with-pings/</guid>
      <description>Throughout the years I&amp;rsquo;ve been told to turn off ICMP Echo Request (ICMP Type 8) and ICMP Echo Reply (ICMP Type 0), commonly referred to as &amp;ldquo;Ping&amp;rdquo;. Some of these people have been people who should know about this kind of thing, like University teachers and people who work in Network Administration. Their reason: &amp;ldquo;security&amp;rdquo;. I say: &amp;ldquo;bollocks&amp;rdquo;.
Using the old &amp;ldquo;security&amp;rdquo; excuse is bad enough, because as soon as you mention security to someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t actively keep up to date with current and past attacks they tend to assume you do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>127-bit masks vs 64-bit masks on Point-to-Point links</title>
      <link>http://dan.donoghue.eu/127-bit-masks-vs-64-bit-masks-ptp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 15:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dan.donoghue.eu/127-bit-masks-vs-64-bit-masks-ptp/</guid>
      <description>I was looking through the usual subs on Reddit this morning and there was a post about things that scare people, and one of the comments was from someone who&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;scared of IPv6&amp;rdquo;. Fair enough, hex does look intimidating at first, especially when you&amp;rsquo;re only familiar with 32-bit dotted-decimal. Underneath this was a comment that said someting along the lines of &amp;ldquo;you can tell how familiar someone is at IPv6 by whether they use /127 or /64 on their point-to-point links&amp;rdquo;, which is a reference to RFC6164 compared to the commonly spouted &amp;ldquo;use /64s everywere&amp;rdquo; nonsense suggested by a lot of IPv6 learning resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wrong destinations are the way to get there</title>
      <link>http://dan.donoghue.eu/wrong-destination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2016 01:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dan.donoghue.eu/wrong-destination/</guid>
      <description>This evening I was just lounging around thinking about BGP, as you do, and reminded myself about an interesting quirk in IP.
What&amp;rsquo;s BGP got to do with it? The way I was taught BGP at University emphasised using Loopback interfaces to move the single-point-of-failure you&amp;rsquo;d get physical interfaces, to a less-error prone virtual interface. In a basic two router lab setup with loopbacks implemented on both routers, this makes the network look something like the diagram below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting SELinux Contexts the Proper Way</title>
      <link>http://dan.donoghue.eu/setting-selinux-contexts-the-proper-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 05:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dan.donoghue.eu/setting-selinux-contexts-the-proper-way/</guid>
      <description>Almost every mention of SELinux Contexts online references the use of chcon(1) for setting contexts on file and directories. This is a pretty shit way of setting contexts, since these changes don&amp;rsquo;t stay when the file system is relabeled, and with chcon(1) the contexts need to be manually set again after an OS reinstallation.
The proper way to set contexts is to use semanage(8), which appends a new line with the rule to /etc/selinux/targeted/contexts/files/file_contexts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Option 121: My Favourite Option</title>
      <link>http://dan.donoghue.eu/option-121-my-favourite-option/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 09:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dan.donoghue.eu/option-121-my-favourite-option/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll start this post off with this: don&amp;rsquo;t judge my skills on how my home network is setup. I use this setup to test out and learn about different techniques, some good, some bad. I would never setup a client&amp;rsquo;s network the way my home network is, but I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know the best way to do something without trying the wrong ways first.
As part of my server reinstallation, I&amp;rsquo;ve been messing about with the routing on my network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Deluge on CentOS 7</title>
      <link>http://dan.donoghue.eu/building-deluge-on-centos-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 16:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dan.donoghue.eu/building-deluge-on-centos-7/</guid>
      <description>Since the deluge and deluge-web packages are omitted from the CentOS/RHEL and EPEL repositories for EL7, and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t trust some unmaintained 3rd-party repo, I decided to build them from source. The instructions on the Deluge website fail to mention anything about what&amp;rsquo;s needed for CentOS/RHEL distributions so I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll write up what&amp;rsquo;s needed here.
Download the source Get the latest version of the source from the Deluge project&amp;rsquo;s Source Mirror.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridging Router Interfaces in IOS</title>
      <link>http://dan.donoghue.eu/bridging-router-interfaces-in-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 14:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dan.donoghue.eu/bridging-router-interfaces-in-ios/</guid>
      <description>I have a strange network setup in my house with many subnets all over the place. To save from either putting a switch downstairs, or another cable run between downstairs and the main switches upstairs, I ended up just connecting the front-room TV to one of the WAN FastEthernet interfaces and setting up an internally-routed /24 for it. This setup gave the TV access to the Internet, but prevents it from reaching my Plex DLNA server, meaning no TV or films.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
